# updated: 8/21 Chad McKell

### ABOUT

Address 9500 Gilman Dr MC 0099

La Jolla, CA 92093-0099

Phone +1 661 289 4215 Email cmckell@ucsd.edu Website chadmckell.com

Summary I am a Ph.D. student at UC San Diego and a research intern at Facebook Reality

Labs. In my research, I develop computational and mathematical tools for physical simulation and geometry processing. My research has applications in computer music,

computer animation, virtual reality, and other fields.

### **EDUCATION**

| 9/19-       | University of California San Diego, Ph.D. in Computer Music                     |
|-------------|---|
|             | GPA: 4.0. Coursework: acoustics, computer graphics, DSP, differential geometry. |
|             | Dissertation topic: computational geometric techniques for sound synthesis.     |
|             | Advisors: Albert Chern, Tamara Smyth, and Miller Puckette.                      |
| 9/16-10/17  | University of Edinburgh, M.S. in Acoustics and Music Technology                 |
| , ,         |   |
| 8/09-12/15  | Wake Forest University, M.S. in Physics   |
| 6/02 - 8/09 | Brigham Young University, B.S. in Biophysics                                    |

# PROFESSIONAL EMPLOYMENT

| 8/21-      | Facebook Reality Labs, Research Intern (Acoustics)              |
|------------|---|
| 7/18-7/19  | Applied Research in Acoustics, R&D Scientist (Acoustics)        |
| 10/14-8/16 | J.P. Morgan/Neovest, Software Development Engineer in Test (QA) |
| 9/12-12/12 | Bennett Aerospace, Engineering Intern                           |

## ACADEMIC EMPLOYMENT

| 9/19-      | University of California San Diego, Teaching Assistant/Researcher (Music)     |
|------------|---|
| 9/12-12/12 | University of North Carolina School of the Arts, Adjunct Instructor (Physics) |
| 9/09-9/11  | Wake Forest University, Teaching Assistant (Physics)                          |
| 9/08-6/09  | Brigham Young University, Tutorial Lab Assistant (Physics)                    |
| 8/07-3/09  | Brigham Young University, Research Assistant (Philosophy)                     |
|            |   |

# CONSULTING

| 5/18-5/18 | <b>Moog Music</b> : Audio effects development in C++ for digital sound synthesizers.  |
|-----------|---|
| 4/17-9/17 | <b>Lofelt</b> : Audio algorithm development and mathematical modeling for audio-haptic devices, including the Razer Nari Ultimate headphones. |

#### PROFESSIONAL RESEARCH ACTIVITIES

8/21- Facebook Reality Labs, Research Intern

La Jolla, California. Research areas: acoustics, applied mathematics. Research topics: spatial audio, numerical simulation, parallel programming, discrete complex analysis. Supervisor: Sebastian Prepeliță.

,

7/18–7/19 Applied Research in Acoustics, R&D Scientist

Culpeper, Virginia. Research areas: acoustics, digital signal processing. Research topics: underwater acoustics, sonar technology, matched filtering, sparse estimation, beamforming. Supervisor: Jonathan Botts.

### ACADEMIC RESEARCH ACTIVITIES

9/19- University of California San Diego, Ph.D. Student

La Jolla, California. Research areas: acoustics, applied mathematics, digital signal processing. Research topics: spatial audio, elastoplasticity, discrete differential geometry, non-Euclidean geometry. Advisors: Albert Chern, Tamara Smyth, and Miller Puckette.

1/17–8/17 University of Edinburgh, Master's Student

Edinburgh, Scotland. Research areas: acoustics, digital signal processing. Research topics: speech synthesis, structural acoustics, modal synthesis, finite-difference time-domain methods. Advisor: Stefan Bilbao.

Wake Forest University, Master's Student Winston-Salem, North Carolina. Research areas: optics, fluid dynamics. Research topics:

optical trapping, laser beam characterization, fluid diffusion. Advisor: Keith Bonin.

8/07–8/09 Brigham Young University, Undergraduate Student

Provo, Utah. Research areas: biophysics, condensed matter physics. Research topics:

membrane biophysics, atomic force microscopy. Advisor: David Busath.

### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

1/10-9/13

UCSD

| <u>C C D D</u>             |  |
|----------------------------|--|
| MUS 5                      | Sound in Time—TA. Spring 2020 (1 term).                            |
| MUS 6                      | Electronic Music—TA. Fall 2020 (1 term).                           |
| MUS 15                     | Popular Music: David Bowie—TA. Winter 2021 (1 term).               |
| MUS 15                     | Popular Music: Video Game Music—TA. Winter 2020 (1 term).          |
| MUS 172                    | Computer Music II—TA. Spring 2021 (1 term).                        |
| UNCSA                      |  |
| SCI 1100                   | General Physics—Instructor. Fall 2012 (1 term).                    |
| $\overline{	ext{WFU}}$     |  |
| PHY 113                    | General Physics I (Mechanics)—TA. 2009–2011 (4 terms).             |
| PHY 114                    | General Physics II (E&M)—Tutor. Fall 2010 (1 term).                |
| $\underline{\mathbf{BYU}}$ |  |
| PHSCS 105                  | General Physics 1 (Mechanics)—Tutor. 2008–2009 (2 terms).          |
| PHSCS 106                  | General Physics 2 (E&M)—Tutor. Winter 2009 (1 term).               |
| PHSCS 121                  | Principles of Physics 1 (Mechanics)—Tutor. 2008–2009 (2 terms).    |
| PHSCS 123                  | Principles of Physics 2 (Waves/Thermo)—Tutor. W/Sp 2009 (2 terms). |
| PHSCS 220                  | Principles of Physics 3 (E&M)—Tutor. W/Sp 2009 (2 terms)           |
|                            |  |

#### PH.D. COURSEWORK

| CSE 167  | Computer Graphics I (Jürgen Schulze)                 |
|----------|--|
| CSE 169  | Computer Animation—audit (Steve Rotenberg)           |
| CSE 274  | Discrete Differential Geometry (Albert Chern)        |
| CSE 291  | Physical Simulation—audit (Steve Rotenberg)          |
| CSE 299  | Differential Geometry Research (Albert Chern)        |
| MUS 206  | Deep Learning for Music Generation (Shlomo Dubnov)   |
| MUS 206  | Computational Acoustic Modeling (Tamara Smyth)       |
| MUS 206  | Spatial Audio (Shahrokh Yadegari)                    |
| MUS 270A | Digital Audio Processing (Tamara Smyth)              |
| MUS 270B | Analysis of Musical Sound (Miller Puckette)          |
| MUS 270C | Compositional Algorithms (Miller Puckette)           |
| MUS 270D | Advanced Projects in Computer Music (Puckette/Smyth) |
| MUS 298  | Spatial Audio Research (Puckette/Smyth/Dubnov)       |

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

## Journal Articles

(1) C. McKell and K. Bonin, "Optical corral using a standing-wave Bessel beam," *Journal of the Optical Society of America B*, Vol. 35, No. 8, 1910–1920, 2018.

## Conference Proceedings

(2) C. McKell, "Sonification of Optically-Ordered Brownian Motion," In Proceedings of the International Computer Music Conference (ICMC), Utrecht, Netherlands, September 2016.

### Master's Theses

- (3) C. McKell, Real-Time Physical Modeling for Haptic Feedback Rendering, Final Project Dissertation, University of Edinburgh, Acoustics and Audio Group, 2017. (Advisor: Stefan Bilbao).
- (4) C. McKell, Finite-Difference Simulations of Speech with Wall Vibration Losses, Special Project Dissertation, University of Edinburgh, Acoustics and Audio Group, 2017. (Advisor: Stefan Bilbao).
- (5) **C. McKell**, Confinement and Tracking of Brownian Particles in a Bessel Beam Standing Wave, Master's Thesis, Wake Forest University, Department of Physics, 2015. (Advisor: Keith Bonin).

# **Technical Reports**

(6) C. McKell, H. Conley, and D. Busath, "AFM Study of Structural Changes in Supported Planar DPPC Bilayers Containing General Anesthetic Isoflurane," Brigham Young University, Paper 827, 2010.

#### Conference Abstracts

(7) K. Bonin and C. McKell, "Tracking Brownian Particles in a Standing-Wave Bessel Beam 2D Optical Trap," SPIE: Optical Trapping and Optical Micromanipulation, XIV Meeting, 2017.